<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter id="blackberry">
   <chapterinfo>
      <author>
         <firstname>openmobster</firstname>
         <surname>at gmail.com</surname>
         <email>openmobster@gmail.com</email>
      </author>
   </chapterinfo>
   <title>Blackberry</title>
   <sect1>
   		<title>Blackberry</title>
   		 <para>
			The Blackberry platform by <ulink url="http://www.blackberry.com">Research In Motion Limited</ulink> is the first mobile platform supported
			by the <emphasis role="bold">OpenMobster Cloud Platform</emphasis>.
   		 </para>
   		 <sect2>
   		 	<title>System Requirements</title>
   		 	<para>
   		 		<itemizedlist>
   		 			<listitem>Java SE JDK v6.0</listitem>
   		 			<listitem>Eclipse 3.4 (the JDE plugin does not run on 3.5 yet)</listitem>
   		 			<listitem>Windows® 2000 SPI or later, or Windows XP</listitem>
   		 			<listitem>Windows Vista (BlackBerry JDE v4.2.1 and higher)</listitem>
   		 			<listitem>Monitor with a resolution of 1024 x 768 or higher</listitem>
   		 		</itemizedlist>
   		 	</para>
   		 </sect2>
   		 <sect2>
   		 	<title>Some Helpful Development Tips</title>
   		 	<para>
   		 		<itemizedlist>
   		 			<listitem>
   		 				The SDK is available at: <ulink url="http://na.blackberry.com/eng/developers/javaappdev/devtools.jsp">Blackberry SDK</ulink>
   		 			</listitem>
   		 			<listitem>
   		 				OpenMobster has been developed using this environment: <emphasis>Blackberry JDE Plug-in for Eclipse v1.0 (with the BlackBerry JDE v4.5 Component Pack)</emphasis>
   		 			</listitem>
   		 			<listitem>
   		 				The platform version supported is version 4.3.0+. The Blackberry platform is fully backward compatible
   		 			</listitem>
   		 			<listitem>
   		 			    Blackberry Development is officially supported only
   		 			    on the Windows Platform. 
   		 			</listitem>
   		 			<listitem>
   		 				Blackberry follows a two-stage compilation process. The first stage called preverification (preverify) pre-verifies
   		 				the Java code and produces the artifact to be processed by the next stage. The next stage called (rapc) actually produces
   		 				the binary that can be installed on the device. The extension of the generated binary is .cod
   		 			</listitem>
   		 			<listitem>
   		 				Moblets/Apps that integrate with the <emphasis>OpenMobster Cloud Platform</emphasis> MUST combine their App's classes with the
   		 				<emphasis role="bold">device-sdk-${project.version}-full.jar</emphasis> library before compiling their App into a binary.
   		 				With the distribution, this library is located under: <emphasis>mobileCloud/blackberry-4.3.0/sdk</emphasis>
   		 			</listitem>
   		 			<listitem>
   		 			    Blackberry has a selected set of APIs which require "signing" the binary (.cod) before installing it on the device. The <emphasis>OpenMobster</emphasis>
   		 			    binaries makes use of these APIs, and hence requires "signing" before installing it on the device. For more information about the
   		 			    "signing" process: <ulink url="http://na.blackberry.com/eng/developers/javaappdev/codekeys.jsp">Signing Process</ulink>
   		 			</listitem>
   		 			<listitem>
   		 			   Code Signing is not required for installing/testing Apps in a simulation environment. In fact all the <emphasis>OpenMobster</emphasis> binaries have been
   		 			   thoroughly tested on a 4.3.0 OS simulator. All tests have passed without any errors, warnings, or crashes.
   		 			</listitem>
   		 			<listitem>
						As of 2.0-M3 community release, all
						<emphasis>OpenMobster</emphasis>
						Blackberry binaries have been signed and tested on an actual
						BlackBerry device. The device used was the BlackBerry Curve 8330 running on the Sprint
						CDMA network.
					</listitem>
   		 		</itemizedlist>
   		 	</para>
   		 </sect2>
   </sect1>
</chapter>
