<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter id="managementConsole">
	<chapterinfo>
		<author>
			<firstname>openmobster</firstname>
			<surname>at gmail.com</surname>
			<email>openmobster@gmail.com</email>
		</author>
	</chapterinfo>
	<title>Management Console</title>
	<sect1>
		<para>
			OpenMobster, comes with a GWT/SmartGWT based GUI Management Console. This Console can be used to administrate users, devices, and push services.
			This tool will evolve over time to include some management functionality like remote wipe, remote lockdown, etc
		</para>
	</sect1>
	<sect1>
		<title>GUI Functionality</title>
		<sect2>
			<title>Create Account</title>
			<para>
			This lets you create an 'Admin' account. This creation has to be approved by another administrator before you can login. 
			</para>
		</sect2>
		<sect2>
			<title>Devices</title>
			<para>
			This lets you manage your devices such activation, deactivation, etc. As the software matures it may add more system level functions like remote wipe, remote lock down, etc. 			
			</para>
			<sect3>
				<title>Activate/De-Activate</title>
				<para>Activates or Deactivates the 'Device' account. If de-activated, none of the Cloud services will be available to the device. They will be available as soon as the account is activated. </para>
			</sect3>
			<sect3>
				<title>Re-assign</title>
				<para>De-activates the 'Device' account and makes it available to be assigned to another user. This is so that when a user leaves, his device can be re-assigned to another user. </para>
			</sect3>
		</sect2>
		<sect2>
			<title>Administrators</title>
			<para>Used for managing the 'Admin' accounts.</para>
			<sect3>
				<title>Activate/De-Activate</title>
				<para>Activates and De-Activates the 'Admin' account. </para>
			</sect3>
		</sect2>
		<sect2>
			<title>Push Setup</title>
			<para>This is used to configure the Apple Push Notification service. As part of the system, a security certificate has to be assigned to an application before messages can be pushed to it.
			This is where your certificate can be uploaded and assigned to an App. Once this is successful, you can send a test push to your iPhone.</para>
		</sect2>
	</sect1>
</chapter>
